Yanely Ramirez

Web Developer & Designer

Casselberry, FL 32707 hello@yanelyramirez.com (239) 850-6672

My love for the digital world started early on, in high school in fact, and ever since I've worked hard towards a way to make my mark on the internet. I've been fortunate to work at places that have helped me expand my skills as both a designer and developer. I really enjoy creating digital experiences from the initial ideas, to coding it to life, it's great to be able carry a project through the stages to launch. From being trusted on big client websites to working on internal products all being used by thousands, it's been a great learning experience so far and am always ready for the next challenge!

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

UI/UX Designer

Stackpath - Winter Park, FL March 2018 to May 2018

While working at StackPath, I worked on a SaaS product by creating wireframes for new aspects of the product in Sketch from requirements, conducted Usability Tests to determine points of improvement, conducted interviews with existing customers to review if current implementations are working, worked hands on in a team environment to deliver within deadlines, used Zeplin to work with developers in handing off designs, worked in Invision and Sketch to bring wireframes to life and add the experience to it all.

UI Developer

Think Agency - Altamonte Springs, FL July 2016 to February 2018

At this marketing agency I created live, working pages out of mockups using CSS, HTML, JS, PHP, and MySQL. I aided in creating responsive designs from brand guidelines, worked in a team to complete projects' tight deadlines, gained knowledge from creating solutions for different clients needs, completed tasks that involved both the front-end and back-end. While working on different projects, I worked with clients to hear feedback and offer solutions while also researching to aid in creating UI mockups for their users needs.

IT Solutions Delivery Intern

Universal Studios Florida - Orlando, FL January 2016 to June 2016

When interning at Universal Studios, I analyzed code alongside Sr. developers, this helped in looking at problems from a different perspective. We used the Agile methodology to work in a large, diverse team environment. I worked on a large, complex e-commerce project and was hands-on with advanced tools such as SDL Tridion, BitBucket, and Gigya.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Web Design and Development

Full Sail University - Winter Park, FL June 2016

Skills

Photoshop, Sketch, HTML 5, CSS3, Javascript, PHP, SQL, SASS, Git, JQuery, JSON, Ajax, Zeplin, Invision, JIRA, Illustrator, Responsive Design, Usability Testing, MongoDB, Wordpress, Web Design, Web Development, User Experience Design, User Interface Design, Mobile Design

Links

https://codepen.io/yxnely/

https://github.com/yxnely

https://linkedin.com/in/yanelyrmz

https://www.yanelyramirez.com/

Awards

Salutatorian

June 2016

Salutatorian - Full Sail Web Design and Development class of June 2016

Advanced Achiever

June 2016

A student from the graduating degree program who has striven to achieve academic excellence and represents the graduating class. This individual puts heart and soul into everything and is willing to extend a hand to fellow students. This individual further embodies the class spirit and is chosen by Course Directors from their degree program.

Course Director's Award - Web Standards Project

June 2016

An honor that is bestowed upon a student who exemplifies the spirit of the class within the course and has taken great time out to understand and enjoy the material.

Additional Information

Bilingual: English & Spanish